好了吗？ 好了
Ready?
嗨… 这是…
Hi,it's
瑞秋… 和…
Rachel and
菲比的家 请…
Phoebe's. Please...
留下… 留下…
-Leave.. -Leave.
等一下，我已经说了“留下” - 我知道，因为你都分到好的字
But I just said "leave."I know because you have all the good words.
而我呢？“这是”、“和” 哦，对不起，我还有个“A”…算了
What do I get? I get "it's," "and." Oh,I'm sorry,I have "a." Forget it.
菲比，别这么小气
-That's silly.
好，那我们交换 不要，我都分到好的字
-All right. So let's switch. -No,I have all the good words.
好吧，我们交换
Okay,fine,fine. We can switch.
嗨… 各位
- Hi... -everybody...
这是… 瑞秋…
-It's... -Rachel...
和… 菲比的家
-and... -Phoebe's.
请…慢着，你怎能这样做啊？ 什么？
Wait. How did you do that?What?
噢，你真是个不简单的室友啊
Oh,you're no ordinary roommate,are you?
这下有好戏可看了
This is gonna be interesting.
菲比，待会再录好吗？ 我想在天黑前去慢跑
Can we finish this later? I'm going running before it gets dark.
你也一起来嘛 真的？
-Why don't you come with me? -Really?
对，一定很好玩，去公园跑步 当做室友间第一次联络感情
It'll be fun! We'll run in the park. It'll be our roommate-bonding thing.
好，我们去跑步
Okay,let's go running!
而且那里有帅哥
-There's cute guys there.
那就朝他们跑过去 好
-Let's run towards them!
你等我一下
Wait just one more second.
嗨，这是瑞秋和菲比的家 请在稍后留下口信，谢谢
Hi,it's Phoebe and Rachel's. Please leave a message. Thanks!
等等，你都讲完了
Wait a minute. You took all the words!
你遇到对手了，瑞秋格林
You've met your match,Rachel Greene!
本集播出： “菲比跑步”
The One Where Phoebe Runs
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
我刚看完一本很棒的书
I just finished this fascinating book.
到了2030年，有些电脑
By the year 2030,there'll be computers...
能执行跟人脑一样多的功能
that can carry out the same amount of functions as a human brain.
所以理论上你可以把思想记忆
So,theoretically,you could download...your thoughts and memories
下载到这种电脑上
into this computer
然后以机器的形态长生不死
and live forever as a machine.
我刚发现我能睁着眼睛睡觉
And I just realized I can sleep with my eyes open.
亲爱的，把箱子钉在地上真是聪明
Honey,it was a great idea,nailing the boxes to the floor.
我没把箱子钉在地上 所以你可以搬走咯
-I didn't nail the boxes to the floor. -So you can move them!
可以，我这就搬
And while I'm doing that,
罗斯有个很好听的电脑故事
Ross has a great computer story for you.
大家好，这是吉宁
Hey,everybody! I'd like you to meet Janine.
她是我的新室友
She's gonna be my new roommate!
艾尔・麦克珀森（著名的泳装模特）
Elle Macpherson
你好
Hi
她要来跟我住
And she's gonna live with me!
很高兴认识你，吉宁… 勒夸，吉宁勒夸
It's nice to meet you. Janine...? -Le Croix.
我都不知道，好好听的姓
I didn't know that. What a pretty last name.
你是哪里人？
So where are you from?
澳大利亚人，几星期前刚到
Australia. I just moved here.
来自地球的另一面？这个我也不知道
From the land down under?I didn't know that either!
你做哪一行？
So what do you do?
我是个舞者 你是个舞者？
-I'm a dancer. -You're a dancer?
她是个舞者
She's a dancer!
我要去整理东西了 我帮你开门
I think I'll go unpack.
乔伊
Joey
你叫她搬来之前有先面试吗？ 当然有
Did you interview her before you asked her to move in?Of course!
你到底问了什么？ “你什么时候可以搬来？”
What did you ask her?When can you move in?
谢谢你把她带到我们身边
Thank you for bringing her into our lives.
难以置信 冷静点，男孩
Unbelievable.Down,boy.
她不是我喜欢的型，她太…
Oh,no,no,no. She's not my type. Not for me,she's not my type. She's too..
美丽、高挑、性感、露肚脐？
Beautiful,tall,sexy,showing her stomach?
你看这堆箱子
Look at all the boxes!
我好想赶快约她
I cannot wait to ask her out.
乔伊，你不能约她 她是你的室友
Wait a minute. You can't. She's your roommate.
那样会很麻烦 没错，千万不要
It'll be too complicated.Yeah,don't do it.
你约了她，我就不能约她了
I mean,if you date her,then I can't date her.
要是你跟她交往又分手呢？ 那就该我行动了
What if you started going out with her and it didn't work out?That's when I make my move.
你之前跟唐娜交往 后来分手
Remember when you broke up with Donna...
记得你们在超市巧遇的尴尬吗
how horrible it was when you bumped into her at the supermarket?
没错
Oh,God,yeah.
想像你住在超市里 好啊
Now imagine you live at the supermarket.Okay!
不
No
你说得对，那样很不好 我不能约她
You're right! I don't want that. I can't date her.
最好也别跟她调情 住得这么近可能会出事
You'd better watch the flirting too,because it could be trouble.
太难了，毕竟美女当前 我很难不打情骂俏
Well,that's gonna be tough,Mon.It's hard for me to be around an attractive woman and not flirt.
我老是在你面前，你也没怎样
You're around me all the time,and you don't flirt.
有点难过是吧？
A little sad about that,sweetie?
我要绑鞋带，你先跑，我就来 好
I have to tie my shoes,so you go ahead. I'll catch up.
拜托，那哪叫跑步，快点
Come on,that's not running! Let's go!
我是说真的，她跑步的时候就像青蛙克米特（《芝麻街》中的角色） 和六百万美元先生（电视剧《无敌金钢》中的角色）的合体
I'm telling you,when she runs...she looks like Kermit the Frog and the Six Million Dollar Man.
莫妮卡以前对他很迷恋哦
Monica had such a crush on him.
她睡觉之前都会亲他的海报
She used to kiss his poster every night before she went to bed.
我也会
I used to do that too!
你有他的专辑 “全身绿色的烦恼”吗？
Did you also have his album,"It's Not Easy Being Green"?
莫妮卡…
Oh,Mon.
所以菲比的姿势很怪？
So Phoebe runs weird,huh?
对，而且她还会想再去跑 我躲不掉，我跟她住在一起
Yeah. And I know she'll want to run again.I don't know how to get out of it. I mean,I live with her.
你就实话实说嘛
Why don't you be straight with her? Tell her the truth.
你说得对，我应该跟她直说
You're right. I should just tell her the truth.
菲比，莫妮卡把我绊倒 我再也不能跑步了
Phoebe,Monica tripped me. I don't think I can ever run again,ever!
但是我们跑得好开心 那些帅哥都在看我们
But we were having so much fun. All those cute guys were checking us out.
就是啊，他们都瞪着我们看
I know. They were definitely staring.
你为什么要绊倒她？ 我不知道
Why? Why would you do that?I don't know.
瑞秋，抱歉害你两个脚踝受伤
Rachel,I'm sorry I hurt your ankles.
只有一个 等着瞧
-Ankle. -We'll see.
好，东西都拿出来了 多谢帮忙
Okay. I am officially unpacked.Thanks for helping me,man.
乔伊？
Joe?
看来他回家了
Well,I guess Joey went home.
看，还有一个箱子没拆
And look,there is still one box I have to unpack.
你被骗了
I got you!
天哪，我差点被吓出心脏病
Oh,my God,you almost gave me a heart attack.
我憋笑憋得好辛苦
It was so hard not to laugh.
这里真的不错 不赖吧？莫妮卡今天要加班
Hey,the place looks great.Not bad,right?Monica's working late,
我要把这里打扫得一尘不染
so I'm gonna make this place spotless.
还有还有 我还要下楼去买花送她
You know what else I'll do?I'm gonna go downstairs and get her some flowers.
谁会不想跟我住？ 我不想
Who wouldn't want to live with me?I don't.
我想跟性感的澳洲舞者住
No,I want to live with the super-hot Australian dancer!
情况如何？你能不打情骂俏吗
How's that going? Are you okay with the not-flirting thing?
目前还可以，但是好累
So far. But it's tough.
我的调情能量一直累积 无处发泄
I've got this built-up flirting energy,and I don't know how to get rid of it.
你好吗？
How you doing?
滚啦
Get out!
天哪
Oh,man!
抱歉，客厅比较宽
Sorry. There's just more room out here.
不是，我只是想到 我也该拉拉筋了
No,you just reminded me that I have to do my stretches too.
你应该…
Why don't you try to be...?
怎么了？
-What's wrong?
没事，你不要碰我 我拉筋拉得全身是汗
-Nothing.I didn't want you to touch me...because I'm all sweaty from the workout.
我去洗个澡
I'm gonna hit the shower.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
抱歉在浴室晾衣服 我的丁字裤很娇贵，不能烘干
Sorry about that stuff hanging in there.It's just my thongs are too delicate for the dryer.
没错，是我 今早我看到你穿了跑鞋溜出来
Oh,yeah,it's me.I saw you grab your running shoes this morning and sneak out.
你骗我好自己跑步
You lied so you could run by yourself.
不是，我没有，我是…
No,Phoebe,no. I was....
我只是跑跑看… 看我能不能跑，结果可以
I was actually just checking...to see...if I could run. And I can!
拜托，我又不是白痴 等等，菲比
Please,I'm not an idiot.No,wait. Phoebe?
同居真的会让人越来越像
Wow. Couples who live together do start to look alike.
我在忙，有话快说，说完快走
I am working right now. So say what you have to say and leave me alone!
口气也很像
Sound alike too.
莫德…
So,Mondler....
你在干什么？ 你说呢？我在打扫
What are you doing?What does it look like? I am cleaning.
你动她的东西有经过她同意吗
Did you get Monica's authorization to move all her stuff?
没必要，我会把东西都放回去
I don't need that. I'll put everything back.
完全恢复原状吗？
Put it back exactly where you found it?
当然是完全恢复原状
Yes. I'm gonna put it back exactly where I found it.
这种态度对你没有帮助
First of all,that attitude is not helping.
她才不会在乎有没有恢复原状
She won't care if I put her stuff back in the same stupid place.
你是刚认识莫妮卡吗？
Hello? Did you just meet Monica?
她会认同我的努力并感动
She'll recognize that I did a nice thing...and appreciate it.
其实这样也蛮好的
Actually,this will work out well.
等你必须搬回去跟乔伊住 乔伊的新室友就可以来跟我住
Because when you move back with Joey...Joey's hot new roommate can come live with me.
我懂了，你想吓我
Oh,I see. You're trying to freak me out.
钱德，莫妮卡对这种事有怪癖
Chandler,Monica is really weird about this kind of stuff,all right?
相信我，我跟她住了16年 她会捉狂
Believe me,I lived with her for 16 years. She's going to freak out.
天哪，她会压在你身上
Oh,my God. She's going to sit on you.
不过她现在瘦了应该不会弄伤你
That probably won't hurt as much anymore.
她才不会，我证明给你看 我现在就打给她
No,she is not. I'll prove it to you.I'll call her right now.
电话擦好了
Phone's done.
莫妮卡，你好吗？ 烂透了
-Hey,Mon. How's it going? -Terrible.
什么事都得我自己来 其他人只会搞砸
If I want something done right,I have to do it myself.Other people just wreck stuff.
我今晚可能会杀人
I think I might kill someone tonight.
别这样，没那么糟吧
Come on,it can't be that bad.
是非常糟，想到快见到你了 我才撑得下去
It's worse.The only thing getting me through...is knowing I'll see you soon.
我看看能不能提早下班 不要…
I might even try to get out of here early.
餐厅似乎很需要你
It sounds like they need you there.
你跟罗斯在一起吗？ 一切都很好，再见
-You're just hanging out with Ross? -It's all good! Okay,bye!
她会宰了我
She's gonna kill me.
电话放反了
The phone was facing the other way.
相框应该摆在上面
And that goes back up there.
好，一切都在掌握中
This is good. This is under control.
我们从大型家具复原起 比较简单
We should start with the big stuff.That'll be the easiest.
先搬沙发
Let's start with the couch.
我没问题
I got it.
位置好像不对
That doesn't look right.
什么意思？ 沙发刚好跟毯子对齐
What are you talking about? The couch is in line with the carpet.
我可以走到这边 轻松的把脚翘在…
Then I can just walk over here and casually put my feet up on....
好，这就是我们干的，那就把沙发往茶几那边推
Okay,here's what we do.We move the couch closer to the coffee table.
那沙发的背后 就不会跟毯子边缘对齐了
But then the back of the couch won't line up with the carpet.
那就把茶几往沙发那边推
Well,we'll just move the coffee table...closer to the couch.
那茶几就不在座位区正中央了
But then the coffee table won't be centered in the seating area.
那茶几就哇哇哇…罗斯
But the coffee table doesn't match the table!
我该怎么办？
Look,what am I gonna do?
我不调情，却还是吸引着她 就像火吸引着飞蛾
I'm not flirting,but I'm drawing her to me like a moth to a flame!
这里是怎么了？
What the hell's going on over here?
莫妮卡会宰了你
Monica's gonna kill you!
我需要你们的帮忙 我得想办法把这个女人吓跑
I need your help.I have to do something to repel this woman.
等等，你们最会把女人吓跑了
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.You guys repel women all the time!
我可是结过三次婚
Hey,I've been married three times.
不，我亲眼见识过
No,I've seen it happen.
你们跟女人交往得好好的 最后却总是能搞砸
You get a rapport going with a woman,but somehow you manage to kill it.
一次一次又一次
Time after time after time after time.
你们的秘诀是什么？
What's your secret?
我们并不会把女人吓跑 完全没有这回事
We do not repel women,okay?That is completely untrue.
我们确实会
Oh,yes,we do,my man.
记不记得大学参加春季舞会 你走向你喜欢的女生
Remember when we went to a dance...and you walked up to that girl you liked
却大谈爱尔兰马铃薯饥荒（十九世纪中叶）？
and talked...about the lrish potato famine?
那你呢？你当年也没那么酷
What about you? You weren't so hot either.
他每次说完话都会加叭噜砰锵
After everything he said,he'd go..
莫妮卡也不喜欢 也许我应该改掉
Monica doesn't like that either. I should stop doing that.
对了，女生不喜欢我聊科学 不只是女生
Girls don't like it when I start talking about science.That's not specific to girls.
太好了，还有呢？
This is great. What else?
她们不喜欢你纠正她们的文法
They don't like you correcting their grammar.
她们不喜欢你解释 你的笑话哪里好笑
And they don't like it when you explain why your jokes are funny.
她们不喜欢你一直问她们 喜不喜欢你
They don't like it when you keep asking them if they like you.
天哪，幸好我有莫妮卡 我再也别想谈恋爱了
-Man,I am so lucky I have Monica. -I'm never gonna find love again.
菲比，可以跟你谈一谈吗？ 好啊
-Can I talk to you for a second? -Sure.
好，我…
Okey，um，I…
菲比，我只是想跟你道歉
Phoebe,I just wanted to say I'm sorry,okay?
我处理得很差 而且我不该骗你
I handled the situation horribly.And I should not have lied to you.
那你应该怎样？
So what should you have done?
我应该跟你说实话
I should have told you the truth.
而实话是…
Which is?
我之所以不想跟你跑步 是因为…
Well,the reason I didn't want to go running with you is...because...
你跑步的姿势有点…
the way that you run is just a little....
所以呢？ 很尴尬，别人都当我们是疯子
-So? -It's embarrassing.People were looking at us like we were crazy.
你干嘛在意？ 因为他们是人
-Why do you care? -Because they're people!
你不认识也不会再见到的人
People you don't know and will never see again.
但他们依旧是人，有眼睛
Yes,but still they are people...with eyes
我就不怕跟喘气小姐跑步
I didn't get embarrassed running next to Miss....
但是好吧，难怪你会觉得 跟我跑步很尴尬
But okay.I can see why running with me would be embarrassing to you.
你很保守
Okay. You're uptight.
我哪有保守
What? I am not uptight.
我才不保守，老兄
I am not uptight,man.
没关系，我不是在批评你 你就是这样
That's okay. I'm not judging you. That's just who you are.
我就比较自由 我从小就这样跑
I'm more free,you know. I run like I did when I was a kid...
因为这样才好玩
because that's the only way it's fun,you know?
你从来没有往前冲到 腿好像快断了吗？
Didn't you ever run so fast you thought your legs would fall off...
例如要跑去玩荡秋千 或是在躲“撒旦”时？
Like when you were running towards the swings or running away from Satan?
邻居的狗
The neighbor's dog.
这盏灯没摆错吧？ 管他的，我会把女人吓跑
Is this in the right place?Who cares? I repel women.
不行！你不能进来 罗斯光着身体
You can't come in here!Ross is naked!
什么？
What？
我不能说我光着身体 她可以看我光着身体
I couldn't say I was naked,because she's allowed to see me naked.
为什么一定要有人光着身体？
Why does anyone have to be naked?
罗斯为什么光着身体？
Why is Ross naked?
我要给钱德看一个东西
I had to show Chandler something.
光着身体看？
Naked?
对，我好像有一点男生的小问题
I guess I have...a "guy" problem.
跟钱德的一样吗？
Is it the same thing Chandler had?
待会再回来 我们搞定了你再回来
We'll get everything squared away,and you can come back later!
好，浴室洗手台底下 还有钱德的药
There's still some of Chandler's medicine in the bathroom.
再见
-Bye. -Bye!
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你有什么病？
Dude,what'd you have?
没时间了，我们必须专心 我们得把一切恢复原状
We have no time,okay? We must focus.We've got to get everything back into its original place.
相簿 相簿里有一大堆这里的照片
The photo album!There were millions of pictures of the apartment in the photo album.
我们可以拿照片来对
We just match everything to the pictures!
太好了，好主意
That's perfect! That's brilliant!
说真的，你有什么病？
What'd you have?
乔伊，我帮你买了啤酒
I've got some beer for you.
你就不能说是给某人买？
Don't you mean "for whom"?
好
Sure.
我正想叫披萨，你要一起吃吗
I was gonna order some pizza. You wanna share one?
披萨，我又不是没吃过 叭噜砰锵
Pizza? It's not like I never had that before.
有什么问题吗？ 爱尔兰马铃薯饥荒令我很沮丧
Is something wrong?Yeah. I'm depressed about that Irish potato famine.
我是指对我 你对我的态度总是怪怪的
No,I mean with me. Because you seem to be acting really weird around me.
好吧，我就明说了
All right,all right.Let's just get this out in the open,okay?
你很火辣，我很俊俏
You're hot.I'm lovable.
我们两个显然很有感觉 但我们是室友
Clearly,there's a vibe going on between us.But we're roommates...
我们不能走上这条路
and it's a huge mistake for us to continue down this road.
乔伊… 不，我是说真的
Joey… No，no，no，I'm telling ya
想像你住在超市里 这样你就懂了
Imagine living in a supermarket...and you'll understand.
所以我们该怎么办？
Okay? So the question is,what do we do?
不怎么办，我觉得你人很好
There isn't anything to do.I think you're really sweet.
但是我对你没兴趣
But I'm not interested in you like that.
不是…
No,I mean....
你人真的很好 我很高兴能当你的室友和朋友
You're a nice guy,and I'm happy to be your roommate and your friend.
只是我对你没有那种感觉
I'm just,you know,I just...don't feel that way about you.
我知道了
I see what happened.
因为我一直躲着你
It's because I was trying to repel you.
相信我，等我一放电 情况就不同了
Right? Believe me,you'd feel a lot different if I turned it on.
应该不会 绝对会
-I don't think so. -Oh,I do.
你好吗？
How you doing?
我很好
I'm okay.
什么？
What?
怎样？
我的天哪
Oh,dear God!
对不起，你说得对，感觉好爽
I'm so sorry. You're right. This feels great!
对吧？你不会在意别人的目光 才几秒钟你就跑不见了
And you don't care if people stare. It's only a second. Then you're gone!
没错，感觉真的好棒 我觉得好自由好过瘾
It's amazing! I feel so free and so graceful!
小心那匹马…抱歉
Watch out for the horse.
我可以进去了吗？
Can I come in now?
为什么东西都变了？ 再见
-Why is everything different? -Bye.
没有变啊，只不过你一进来 房里变得更亮了
I don't see anything different...other than the fact that the room got brighter when you came into it.
小茶几位置不对，沙发怪怪的 更别提冰箱上的磁铁
The end table is wrong,the couch looks bizarre...and don't even get me started on the refrigerator magnets.
你别生气，我整理完东西 想做点让你高兴的事
Okay,don't be mad,okay?After I unpacked the boxes,I wanted to do something nice for you...
所以我就大扫除
so I cleaned the apartment.
我把东西乱搬 却忘了该怎么复原
So I moved everything around,and then I forgot...where it went back.
对不起，对不起对不起
I'm sorry,I'm very sorry,I'm sorry.
没关系 钱德，你在怕我吗？
That's okay.Are you afraid of me or something?
你要我怕你吗？
Do you want me to be afraid of you?
当然不要
Of course not.
拜托，你做了这么棒的事 我真的很开心
My gosh,Chandler,what you did is a wonderful thing...and I really appreciate it.
我知道我对东西的摆设有怪癖 但我万万没想到你会担心
I have this thing where I want everything in the perfect place.But I'd never expect you to worry about that.
真的？ 当然是真的
Really?Of course.
你最好了，过来我抱抱
Oh,you're the best.You come here to me.
等等，先做该做的事
Hold on,okay? First things first.
罗斯光着身体时坐过哪里？
Did Ross sit anywhere while he was naked?
书上说到了2030年
It said that by the year 2030...
有些电脑 能执行跟人脑一样多的功能
there'll be computers carrying out the same number of functions...as an actual human brain.
所以理论上人可以把思想记忆 下载到这种电脑上
So,theoretically,you could download your thoughts...and your memories into this computer..
然后以机器的形态长生不死
And live forever as a machine.
吉宁，你知道我们现在在做什么吗？
Janine,do you know what we're doing right now?
你和我，我们在连结
You and I,we're interfacing.
我该走了
I gotta go.